<resources>
    <string name="app_name">android_Country_Profile</string>
    <string name="BD_text">Bangladesh</string>
    <string name="Pak_text">Pakistan</string>
    <string name="India_text">India</string>


    <string name="bd_des">
        Bangladesh, to the east of India on the Bay of Bengal, is a South Asian country marked by lush greenery and many waterways.
        Its Padma (Ganges), Meghna and Jamuna rivers create fertile plains, and travel by boat is common.
        On the southern coast, the Sundarbans, an enormous mangrove forest shared with Eastern India, is home to the royal Bengal tiger.\n\n
        Capital: Dhaka\n
        Dialing code: +880\n
        Prime minister: Sheikh Hasina\n
        Population: 163 million (2016) \n
        President: Abdul Hamid\n\n
        Background:\n\n
        The huge delta region formed at the confluence of the Ganges and Brahmaputra River systems - now referred to as Bangladesh - was a loosely incorporated outpost of various empires centered on the Gangetic plain for much of the first millennium A.D. Muslim conversions and settlement in the region began in the 10th century, primarily from Arab and Persian traders and preachers. Europeans established trading posts in the area in the 16th century. Eventually the area known as Bengal, primarily Hindu in the western section and mostly Muslim in the eastern half, became part of British India. Partition in 1947 resulted in an eastern wing of Pakistan in the Muslim-majority area, which became East Pakistan. Calls for greater autonomy and animosity between the eastern and western wings of Pakistan led to a Bengali independence movement. That movement, led by the Awami League (AL) and supported by India, won the independence war for Bangladesh in 1971.
        The post-independence AL government faced daunting challenges and in 1975 was overthrown by the military, triggering a series of military coups that resulted in a military-backed government and subsequent creation of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) in 1978. That government also ended in a coup in 1981, followed by military-backed rule until democratic elections occurred in 1991. The BNP and AL alternated in power between 1991 and 2013, with the exception of a military-backed, emergency caretaker regime that suspended parliamentary elections planned for January 2007 in an effort to reform the political system and root out corruption. That government returned the country to fully democratic rule in December 2008 with the election of the AL and Prime Minister Sheikh HASINA. In January 2014, the incumbent AL won the national election by an overwhelming majority after the BNP boycotted, extending HASINA's term as prime minister. With the help of international development assistance, Bangladesh has reduced the poverty rate from over half of the population to less than a third, achieved Millennium Development Goals for maternal and child health, and made great progress in food security since independence. The economy has grown at an annual average of about 6% over the last two decades and the country reached World Bank lower-middle income status in 2014.

    </string>

    <string name="pak_des">
        Pakistan, officially the Islamic Republic of Pakistan, is a country in South Asia.
        It is the fifth-most populous country with a population exceeding 212,742,631 people.
        In area, it is the 33rd-largest country, spanning 881,913 square kilometres.\n\n
        Capital: Islamabad\n
        Prime minister: Imran Khan\n
        President: Mamnoon Hussain\n
        Population: 193.2 million (2016)\n
        Currency: Pakistani rupee</string>

    <string name="in_des">
        India is a vast South Asian country with diverse terrain – from Himalayan peaks to Indian Ocean coastline – and history reaching back 5 millennia.
        In the north, Mughal Empire landmarks include Delhi’s Red Fort complex and massive Jama Masjid mosque, plus Agra’s iconic Taj Mahal mausoleum.
        Pilgrims bathe in the Ganges in Varanasi, and Rishikesh is a yoga centre and base for Himalayan trekking.\n\n
        Capital: New Delhi\n
        Dialing code: +91\n
        President: Ram Nath Kovind\n
        Population: 1.324 billion (2016)\n
    </string>
</resources>
